{
  "reference_number": "9559",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": "The danger of setting a target in legislation now is that it will reflect short-lived climate pollutants, such as methane, that recent\n science shows will overstate its Global Warming Potential as “CO2-equivalent” emissions. The conventional New Zealand stocktake is\n heavily skewed towards methane from primary land use when expressed as “CO2-equivalent” emissions. A recent study (see\n\n https://www.nature.com/articles/s41612-018-0026-8) co-authored by VUW's Professor Frame and colleagues from Oxford University\n and the University of Reading as well as Norway's Centre for International Climate and Environmental Research, exaggerated the long-\n\n term effects of methane on the climate. CO2 is a stock pollutant that accumulates in the atmosphere whereas methane is a flow\n pollutant, which disappears about a decade after its emissions occur. Consequently, as this is new science that could reshape the\n New Zealand profile, it is better to have the net zero target but leave it to the Commission to advise Government on the specific\n\n target."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": "CO2 should be the target gas given it accumulates and by targeting this one gas other solutions will likely arise to flow emissions."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The concept of CO2-e emissions is deeply embedded in climate policy despite its weaknesses. Before any Budget can be\n\n established, there must be a fundamental reassessment of the inventory in light of stock and flow climate pollutants."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The authors of A solution to the misrepresentations of CO2-equivalent emissions of short-lived climate pollutants under ambitious\nmitigation'' by Myles R. Allen, Keith P. Shine, Jan S. Fuglestvedt, Richard J. Millar, Michelle Cain, David J. Frame & Adrian H. Macey."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This needs a whole of government approach."
    }
  ]
}
